<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to use R on Journalism with R</title>
    <link>/en/how_to_use_r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to use R on Journalism with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/how_to_use_r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio guide</title>
      <link>/en/how_to_use_r/tour_rstudio/rstudio-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/how_to_use_r/tour_rstudio/rstudio-tour/</guid>
      <description>RStudio tour When you first open RStudio, the app is divided into three sections.
Most sections have tabs for even more additional ways to view different sorts of things.
These sections can be customized and placed wherever you want through the RStudio menu options. Preferences &amp;gt; Pane Layout
  The tall section on the left is the console and that’s where you can type in R code to execute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R</title>
      <link>/en/how_to_use_r/intro_to_r/intro-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/how_to_use_r/intro_to_r/intro-to-r/</guid>
      <description>Syntax You must follow pretty specific syntax rules for it to work. R won’t guess for you.
  R is case-sensitive (unlike SQL) intepreted language (unlike C) Can enter commands at prompt &amp;gt; or in batch Comments are preceded by #  This is important to use often in your code for documentation You’ll see it often in this course  Statements are lines of code such as functions and object assignments  Enters in code (as in a new line) or semi-colons will separate statements    Working directories Your working directory is the folder on your computer in which you are currently working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data structures in R</title>
      <link>/en/how_to_use_r/initial_exploration/data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/how_to_use_r/initial_exploration/data-structures/</guid>
      <description>Vectors A vector is a sequence of data elements of the same basic type. The parts that consist of a vector are called components or elements.
vec1 &amp;lt;- c(1,4,6,8,10) vec1 ## [1] 1 4 6 8 10 A vector vec is explicitly constructed by the concatenation function c().
vec1[5] ## [1] 10 Elements in vectors can be addressed by standard [i] indexing
vec1[3] &amp;lt;- 12 vec1 ## [1] 1 4 12 8 10 One of the elements in the array is replaced with a new number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up for this class</title>
      <link>/en/how_to_use_r/project_for_class/class-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/how_to_use_r/project_for_class/class-project/</guid>
      <description>How to a) get the files needed for each chapter in class and b) how to follow along with each chapter/code through.
Getting files and folders The files for this class will include the raw data, the scripts, and r markdown files.
There are a few options to download them:
1) Install the package I’ve created for this class Each chapter has a prompt to download the files associated with each one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R basics, help, mistakes</title>
      <link>/en/how_to_use_r/syntax/r-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/how_to_use_r/syntax/r-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Some R code basics  &amp;lt;- is known as an “assignment operator” – it means “Make the object named to the left equal to the output of the code to the right” &amp;amp; means AND, in Boolean logic | means OR, in Boolean logic ! means NOT, in Boolean logic When referring to values entered as text, or to dates, put them in quote marks like this: &amp;quot;United States&amp;quot;, or &amp;quot;2016-07-26&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>