<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting started on Documentation of theme Hugo Learn (Japanese)</title>
    <link>/jp/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting started on Documentation of theme Hugo Learn (Japanese)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/jp/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolve from Excel to R</title>
      <link>/jp/introduction/from_excel/from-excel-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jp/introduction/from_excel/from-excel-to-r/</guid>
      <description>R is excellent for those who already are used to working with data in spreadsheets.
Switching from Excel or Google Sheets to R for data analysis can seem daunting. Over time, the open-source statistical programming language has consistently grown in popularity among those who work with numbers, with thousands of user-created libraries to expand on its power.
Though it was first created primarily to make it easier to create statistical models and output very basic visuals to explore data, it’s expanded to the point that people can use R to do so many advanced processes such as scrape websites, communicate with APIs, and publish beautiful interactive charts and maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rとは何か</title>
      <link>/jp/introduction/what_is_r/what-is-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jp/introduction/what_is_r/what-is-r/</guid>
      <description>Rとは何でしょうか?  コンピュータを用いた統計とグラフィックのためのプログラミング言語と、その開発実行環境です ベル研究所が開発した“S”言語に基づいています Rはオークランド大のRoss Ihaka　と Robert Gentleman によって1993年に開発されました ## Rは 過去10年間で人気を博してきました 分野の枠を超えた多くのデータアナリストが使っています 手軽なものから、複雑なものまで多くの報道を支えてきました ## なぜRを使うべきなのでしょうか? 無料 オープンソース 最先端のグラフィックスとデータ分析 Windows, Linux, Mac OS Xで動作します 巨大なユーザーベースとコミュニティがあります ## 調査報道の事例 Gun Deaths in America More than 215,000 students have experienced gun violence at school since Columbine Spies in the Skies ## Rでプログラミングするためのインターフェース Rそのもの (以下の全てにおいてBase Rが必要) RStudio (私たちはこのコースで、これを優先的に使います) その他  Eclipse StatET Microsoft Visual Studio R Commander Rattle © Copyright 2018, Andrew Ba Tran    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>